<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record_update table="sys_ui_page">
    <sys_ui_page action="INSERT_OR_UPDATE">
        <category>general</category>
        <client_script/>
        <description/>
        <direct>false</direct>
        <endpoint>x_snc_reactor_manual.do</endpoint>
        <html><![CDATA[<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<j:jelly trim="false" xmlns:j="jelly:core" xmlns:g="glide" xmlns:j2="null" xmlns:g2="null">
<div style="padding-left: 20px;">
<span style="visibility: hidden;">_CUT_HERE_</span>
	<g2:no_escape>$[
		var docapi = new x_snc_devtools.DocumentationAPI('e5879c7fdb39d110dcbdd03cd3961946');
		docapi.RenderHeader();
	]</g2:no_escape>
	
	<p>Welcome to Reactor - created and maintained by&#160;<a href="mailto:sascha.wildgrube@servicenow.com">Sascha Wildgrube</a>.</p>

	<h2>Features</h2> 
	<p>Use Reactor to create React based applications in ServiceNow. Check out the&#160;<a href="/x_snc_reactor_demo.do" target="_blank">Demo</a>!</p>
	<p>In React its all about React components. With Reactor its all about Reactor components.</p>
	<p>A Reactor component may contain a React component class, but its more than that. Reactor components manage the dependencies between the components. Stylesheets are also Reactor components. Think of them as an umbrella of everything you want to make part of your app on the client side.</p>
	<p>Reactor components have a "role" - a category that gives a hint about what it really is. Since React does not dictate any sort of separation of concerns - we have to make up for it. We are well advised to create React components not as a mix of logic and html footprint, but to create components that are for user interaction, others for application logic, etc. Reactor helps you getting there.</p>
	<p>Reactor components can be modified when loaded by using Component Tokens. Tokens are key value pairs that can be searched and replaced in the scripts, style sheets and urls defined by components. Tokens can be simple text strings, references to system properties or be defined by a script.</p>
	<p>Please note: Currently the JavaScript libraries for React (and Babel for JSX support) are loaded from a CDN. This may NOT be compliant with GDPR requirements - so watch out for a future version that supports locally stored libraries.</p>

	<h2>Disclaimer</h2>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderDisclaimer()]</g2:no_escape>	
	
	<h2>System Requirements</h2>
	<ul>
		<g2:no_escape>$[
			docapi.RenderSystemRequirements(
				'Washington,Xanadu',
				true,
				AppGetDependencies());
		]</g2:no_escape>	
	</ul>
	
	<h2>Installation</h2>
	<ol>
		<g2:no_escape>$[
			docapi.RenderInstallationInstructionsImportFromSourceControl(
				'DevTools',
				'https://github.com/saschawildgrube/servicenow-devtools',
				true,
				'https://www.wildgrube.com/servicenow-devtools');
		]</g2:no_escape>
		<g2:no_escape>$[
			docapi.RenderInstallationInstructionsImportFromSourceControl(
				'Reactor',
				'https://github.com/saschawildgrube/servicenow-reactor');
		]</g2:no_escape>		
		<g2:no_escape>$[
			docapi.RenderInstallationInstructionsAppInstall();
		]</g2:no_escape>	
		<g2:no_escape>$[
			docapi.RenderInstallationInstructionsRunTestSuite('f57de710db0e5510dcbdd03cd39619d0');
		]</g2:no_escape>			
	</ol>

	<h2>Setting up a new React app</h2>
	<ol>
		<li>Create a new UI Script to contain the main React component.</li>
		<li>Use the syntax editor macro "react" to get started.</li>
		<li>Create a Reactor Component and refer to the UI Script. The component name and the class name of the React component must be identical.</li>
		<li>Create a UI Page and add the following code into the html body:
			<pre>
				<g2:no_escape>$[
					x_snc_reactor.GetUIPageDemoScript();	
				]</g2:no_escape>					
			</pre>
		</li>
		<li>Ajust the code for your new React component.</li>
		<li>Test the UI page.</li>
	</ol>
			
	<h2>Additional Documentation</h2>
	<ul>
		<li><a href="https://reactjs.org" target="_blank">ReactJS.org</a></li>
		<li><a href="https://reactjs.org/docs/react-api.html" target="_blank">React API</a></li>
		<li><a href="https://babeljs.io/repl" target="_blank">Babel</a></li>
	</ul>

	<h2>React(or) Components</h2>
	<g2:no_escape>$[HtmlRenderReactorComponents('x_snc_reactor')]</g2:no_escape>			

	<h2>Reference</h2>
	
	<h3>Roles</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderRoles()]</g2:no_escape>		

	<h3>Configuration Options</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderProperties()]</g2:no_escape>

	<h3>Tables</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderTables()]</g2:no_escape>		
	
	<h3>Editor Macros</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderEditorMacros()]</g2:no_escape>		

	<!--
	<h3>UI Actions</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderUIActions()]</g2:no_escape>		
	-->
	<h3>Script Includes</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderScriptIncludes()]</g2:no_escape>

	<h3>Dependencies</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderDependencies()]</g2:no_escape>		

	<h3>Technical Debts</h3>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderTechnicalDebts()]</g2:no_escape>		


	<h2>License</h2>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderCopyright(2022,'Sascha Wildgrube')]</g2:no_escape>
	<g2:no_escape>$[docapi.RenderLicense()]</g2:no_escape>
	
	<h2>Release Notes</h2>

	<h3>1.10.0 - TODO</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>Reactor is fully tested with Xanadu.</li>
		<li>Vancouver is no longer actively supported.</li>
		<li>DevTools 1.108.0 is now required.</li>
		<li>Added component RoundedBox.</li>
		<li>Added component TabContainer.</li>
		<li>Added the capability to the ReactorComponent to call the onTimer() function continuously in a given interval.</li>
		<li>Component TabNavigation now also supports ReactorComponents as labels (not only strings).</li>
		<li>Component TabNavigation now also supports closing of tabs via callback function.</li>
		<li>Component TabNavigation property callbackOnClick was renamed to callbackOnSelect.</li>
		<li>Component TreeNavigation is now clearing the filter if collapse options are clicked and calls the callbackOnFilterReset function if provided.</li>
		<li>Component TreeNavigation now only shows items that have sub items that match the filter.</li> 
		<li>Component Workspace no longer uses hard-wired background colors.</li>
		<li>Component Button now uses the Polaris css class names for styling.</li>
		<li>Component Icon no longer intercepts pointer events.</li>
		<li>Component Button now supports a tooltip.</li>
		<li>Component ToolBar now supports tooltips for its buttons.</li>
		<li>Component Clock now uses the ReactorComponent startTimer() function.</li> 
		<li>Installation instructions now also include running the Test Suite.</li>
		<li>Added Table, Dependencies and Technical Debt chapters to the manual.</li>
	</ol>


	<h3>1.9.0 - 2024-07-11</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>Added component ButtonSelection.</li>
		<li>Added component TabNavigation.</li>
	</ol>


	<h3>1.8.0 - 2024-06-03</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>DevTools 1.86.0 is now required because of StringReplaceMultiple().</li>
		<li>Introduced Component Tokens - which allow to replace tokens in scripts, css styles and urls when loading components.</li>
		<li>GoogleMapsAPI component now uses the maps api configuration as defined by OOTB system properties.</li>
	</ol>



	<h3>1.7.0 - 2024-03-31</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>Utah is no longer actively supported.</li>
		<li>Reactor is fully tested in Washington.</li>
		<li>Added component GoogleMaps with auto-centering, auto-zoom, marker, polyline and heatmap support.</li>
	</ol>	
	
	<h3>1.6.0 - 2023-11-29</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>Tokyo is no longer actively supported.</li>
		<li>Reactor has been fully tested in Vancouver.</li>
		<li>DevTools 1.71.0 is now required because of the use of BindAllFunctionsToThis() (introduced in 1.67.0) and the additional parameter support in GetValue() and SetValue(). BindAllFunctionsToThis() is now used in the constructor of ReactorComponent.</li>
		<li>Now using React 18.</li>
		<li>Added a new Reactor Component role: "Theme / Fonts / CSS" and assigned the "Fontawesome" component to that new role.</li>
		<li>The TreeNavigation component now supports text filtering.</li>
		<li>The TreeNavigation component now supports menu collapse and expand.</li>
		<li>The TreeNavigation component also supports to collapse all and expand all menu items and to return to the last user selection.</li>
		<li>The Workspace component now supports an additional left bar header area - e.g. to place a text filter for the tree navigation.</li>
		<li>If the system property x_snc_reactor.logging.verbosity is set to "debug" the development version of React is imported.</li>
		<li>On the Reactor Component form for a script component loaded from a url, the script section was displayed. This has been fixed.</li>
		<li>The Centered component caused content to be cut off on top if the screen size did not fit. This has been fixed.</li>
		<li>HtmlRenderReactorComponents() now enumerates all available roles and renders the contained components dynamically.</li>

	</ol>	

	<h3>1.5.0 - 2023-08-18</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>DevTools 1.66.0 is now required.</li>
		<li>Reactor has been fully tested on Utah.</li>
		<li>San Diego is no longer actively supported.</li>
		<li>Reactor components can now contain "module" scripts.</li>
		<li>Added component ToolBar.</li>
		<li>Added component TreeNavigation.</li>
		<li>Added component InfoMessage.</li>
		<li>Added component WarningMessage.</li>
		<li>Added component Fullscreen.</li>
		<li>Added component Workspace.</li>
		<li>Added component Centered.</li>
		<li>Renamed AllTables to AllTablesController but AllTables is still available for backward compatibility.</li>
	</ol>

	
	<h3>1.4.0 - 2023-03-24</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>DevTools 1.59.0 is now required.</li>
		<li>Added component ErrorMessage.</li>
		<li>Added component AllTables.</li>
		<li>Added property "text" to the Waiting component.</li>
		<li>Added link to "Demo" page to the application menu.</li>
		<li>The "react" macro boilerplate class now also contains componentDidMount() and componentWillUnmount() member functions.</li>
	</ol>
	
	<h3>1.3.0 - 2022-10-09</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>Added new entity "Component Properties" to properly document the input properties of each Reactor component.</li>
		<li>Added component IFrame.</li>
		<li>Added component Waiting.</li>
		<li>Added component Icon.</li>
		<li>Added component FontawesomeCSS.</li>
		<li>Introduced the Reactor component which contains the ReactorComponent class (derived from React.Component) that serves as a base class for all other React(or) component classes.</li>
		<li>Added ability to load stylesheets from a URL.</li>
		<li>Reactor components are now grouped by their role in the manual.</li>
	</ol>	
	
	<h3>1.2.0 - 2022-09-18</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>DevTools 1.44.0 is now required.</li>
		<li>Reactor Components now also cover stylesheets.</li>
		<li>Added component HeaderMenu.</li>
		<li>Improved and renamed component ReactorDemoApp.</li>
		<li>Added support to include scripts from a URL.</li> 
	</ol>	
	
	<h3>1.1.0 - 2022-09-17</h3>
	<ol>
		<li>Added JSX support.</li>
		<li>The system property x_snc_reactor.active is now used to switch the Reactor app on or off as a whole.</li>
		<li>All navigation modules are now requiring the x_snc_reactor.developer role.</li>
		<li>Fixed Render() html output structure.</li> 
	</ol>	
	
	<h3>1.0.0 - 2022-09-17</h3>
	<p>First baselined version</p>

<span style="visibility: hidden;">_CUT_HERE_</span>
</div>
</j:jelly>]]></html>
        <name>manual</name>
        <processing_script/>
        <sys_class_name>sys_ui_page</sys_class_name>
        <sys_created_by>admin</sys_created_by>
        <sys_created_on>2022-09-16 13:55:46</sys_created_on>
        <sys_id>ed7de710db0e5510dcbdd03cd39619cb</sys_id>
        <sys_mod_count>118</sys_mod_count>
        <sys_name>manual</sys_name>
        <sys_package display_value="Reactor WORK IN PROGRESS" source="x_snc_reactor">e5879c7fdb39d110dcbdd03cd3961946</sys_package>
        <sys_policy/>
        <sys_scope display_value="Reactor WORK IN PROGRESS">e5879c7fdb39d110dcbdd03cd3961946</sys_scope>
        <sys_update_name>sys_ui_page_ed7de710db0e5510dcbdd03cd39619cb</sys_update_name>
        <sys_updated_by>admin</sys_updated_by>
        <sys_updated_on>2024-12-13 11:58:38</sys_updated_on>
    </sys_ui_page>
</record_update>
